#网友们 它不会扒锅的
My friends, (the chicken) won't stick to the wok
#看见没有 这叫滑油
See? This is "hua you" (pre-frying)
#听见了吧 这个声音就正合适
You hear that? This is the perfect sound
#这是我师爷的传承菜
This dish is the heritage of my master's master
#老式宫保鸡丁
Traditional Kungpao Chicken
#咱这是二荆条（辣椒）师父
This is "Er Jing Tiao" chili pepper, my master
#这蒜片 你看啊
The garlic slices... Look!
#大家看见没有 切成四瓣就行了
Did you see it? Just cut it into four parts
#你看我切得很多 量很大
I've cut a lot of spring onion. We need a huge amount
#葱二 蒜一 姜是零点五
2 portions of spring onion, 1 portion of garlic, and 0.5 portion of ginger
#您今天用的是鸡腿肉吧 对鸡腿肉
-You are using chicken leg today, right?
-Yep, chicken leg
#他就这样 这样斩
It should be cut... cut in this way
#你看见没有 看见没有网友们 你看
Did you see that, guys? Look
#我师父斩切把鸡的皮都去掉了
My master is removing the skin while chopping
#这样炒出来利落
In this way, the chicken dices will be neater after cooking
#嘿 咔咔的 这老头儿
Hey! Cutting it like "ka-ka", my old buddy
#宝刀不老我师父
My master's sword is still sharp
#不老就是长点锈  老不用了
Yeah, just a little rusted. He hasn't used it for a long time
#师父给讲的是原料是基础
As my master used to teach me, ingredients are the foundation of a dish
#就是选料 鸡腿 要选鸡腿
That is, you must choose chicken leg for this dish
#不要用鸡胸 鸡胸就没有口感了
Not chicken breast. Otherwise the texture is wrong
#刀工 现在是斩 刀工是艺术
Knife skills. Now he is chopping. Knife skill is an art.
#待会还要调味 调味是关键
We need to season it later. Seasoning is the key
#小东西都背下来了 可以啊
You can recite it my kid. That's impressive
#你看这剁的干净利落
Look. The chicken dices are cut so neatly
#过去砧板上 三叔知道
Back in the old days... Sanshu, you know
#必须得这么剁
We must chop it this way
#进底味了 调味是关键
Now introducing the basic flavor. Seasoning is the key
#零点五克 很少
0.5 grams. Very little amount (of salt)
#胡椒粉有那么一点
Some white pepper powder as well.
#多点少点这无所谓
A little more or less, it doesn't matter
#酱油 这就差不多了
Soy sauce, almost there
#三叔家的老黄酒
Sanshu's old rice wine (yellow wine)
#想购买黄酒，私信三叔，三叔给大家发链接        #这一句视频中没有打出来
If you want to buy this rice wine, please send Sanshu a private message. Sanshu will send you the link
#先给它抓抓黏 黏度出来
Massage the chicken first until it feels sticky
#蛋清  半个就足够了
Egg white. A half is enough
#葱姜水 现在这些年轻的厨师
Ginger-scallion brine. Nowadays many young cooks...
#根本就没有这个葱姜水这个环节
They don't use ginger-scallion brine at all
#网友你看 这汁儿 浓缩能不香吗
Look, guys. The concentrated juice can't taste bad
#这个鸡丁怎么打
How to massage the chicken?
#你应该这么搂着打 三叔知道
You should do it this way, scoop it up. Sanshu knows
#这么打的才能进去呢
Only in this way can the sauce be absorbed inside
#这个汁才能稠呢 对
-In this way, the sauce will be thick and sticky. -Right
#看似一宫保鸡丁
This Kungpao chicken
#其实为什么有的网友
Actually, why many friends suggested that...
#建议重新再做做
we make it once again
#跟你们讲 腌制这鸡丁呢
In terms of marinating the chicken dices
#必须要在十五分钟 是最合适
It's the best to marinate it for 15 minutes
#不能低于十五分钟
No less than 15 minutes
#也不能太超于十五分钟
But not over 15 minutes too much either
#其实还可以加点水
We can add some water in fact
#加点水 嫩 水要加的要不够
Water makes the chicken tender. If we don't add enough water
#鸡丁的嫩度就不够
The chicken won't be tender enough
#这吃的是嫩
Tenderness is the selling point of chicken
#宫保鸡丁 脆指的是什么啊 花生
What is the "crispy" element in Kungpao chicken? Peanuts.
#所以说千万不要反应过来
So never say that
#说是鸡丁是脆的
The chicken dices should be crispy
#这颜色合适吧 好 太好了
Is the color correct? Yes. Perfect
#我们用点玉米淀粉就行
Let's add some corn starch
#一勺 这一勺 就够了
One spoon. One spoon is enough
#少半勺
half a spoon more
#待会咱们封个油
We will "seal" the chicken with oil later
#封那个二伯那个最牛的油
With Erbai's best oil
#先炸花生米 好嘞
-Fry the peanuts first. -Yay
#过去可以拿烤箱烤 先烤 后炸
In the past we used to roast the peanuts in the oven first. Then fry them
#这样可以保持几天
In this way, the peanuts remain crispy
#它永远是脆的 对
for several days. -Right
#好多人他不知道这事儿
Many people don't know this trick...
#记住了吗 直接炸了 记住了
-... and fry the peanuts directly
-Got it? -Got it.
#烤完了以后 水气都给它烤走了
After roasting, the moisture is gone
#倒花生米 中小火浸炸
Pour the peanuts into the wok. Soak-fry over medium-low heat
#油热了 一定要离开火
If the oil is too hot, you must remove the wok from heat
#其实油呢 有三成就够了
Actually 30% hot (~90 degrees Celcius) is enough
#你看 花生米它要求必须得脱皮
Look. The skin of peanuts must be removed in advance
#这花生米什么时候出锅合适
When should we take the peanuts out of the wok?
#听到花生米的啪啪响的时候
When you hear the "pa-pa" sound
#可以出锅了
The peanuts are ready
#清脆的声音 拿那个勺子 咔咔
The clear sound. Shake them in that spoon... "Ka-ka"
#清脆的声音
The crisp sound
#现在就可以了 微微的见黄 可以了
Now it's done. Slightly yellow. Done!
#听见了吗 这个声音就正合适
You hear that? This is the perfect sound
#这是宫保鸡丁其中一味 叫脆
This is the "crispy" element of Kungpao chicken
#我们把这花椒油炸一下
Let's prepare the peppercorn oil
#四川花椒跟北京的花椒两种啊
Sichuan peppercorn and Peking peppercorn
#一比一 香味出来了
In a ratio of 1:1. Here comes the aroma
#为什么我要离火 你看见没有
Why am I taking the wok away from the fire? You see that?
#炸的花椒 关键点在哪呢
What's the key in frying peppercorn?
#这油温绝对不能特别热 对
-The oil mustn't be overheated. -Yes.
#你不能炸糊了 这是浸炸
The peppercorn shouldn't be burnt. This is soak-frying
#因为它要的是有香气味
Because this dish requires the aroma of the peppercorn
#这个可以了
This is OK
#调一汁儿
Let's make a sauce
#来点蒜 来点姜 葱呢 可以多搁点
Some garlic, some ginger, and some more spring onion
#黄酒
Rice wine (Yellow wine)
#像咱们老饭骨（黄）酒比较纯
We are using relatively strong rice wine here
#不用太多就行
So we don't need too much
#酱油和黄酒是一比一
The ratio of soy sauce to rice wine is 1:1
#醋是它的一半 也不太多
Half that volume of vinegar. Not too much
#三分之二 对
-Two thirds. -Yep
#这糖呢 一勺
-What about sugar? -One spoon
#糖和醋基本上是一比一
Basically the same amount as vinegar.
#对 再来点就够了
Yep. A little bit more
#看看网友们
Take a look guys
#我们给你说的多细多清楚啊
We are telling you all the details
#胡椒粉呢 这个三叔知道
White pepper powder? Sanshu knows about that
#多点少点 可搁可不搁
It doesn't matter if you add more or less, or even omit it
#可多可少 搁点提香
You can add more or less. The white pepper powder enhances the aroma
#这盐呢 千万别多了
Not too much salt!
#那么一点足够了 再来一点吧
-That is enough. -Some more
#因为你的底味稍微的窄
Because the basic flavor is not strong enough
#我们还可以再提点老抽色
We can also add some dark soy sauce to darken the color
#然后 水淀粉 这个就够了
Then slurry. That's enough
#葱下去了
Add the spring onion
#还浅一点
The color is lighter than it should be
#这个颜色也浅 对
The color of the chicken is also too light
#再来一点  今天师爷非常慎重
Some more dark soy sauce please. The master is very cautious today
#小心的给你们做这个菜
Cooking this dish very carefully for you guys
#正好 这欢子真棒
That's perfect. Huanzi is awesome
#行 这回足够了
Cool. Enough this time
#刚才的花椒油 现在凉了以后
The peppercorn oil is cooled down now
#咱们封上油
Let's seal the chicken with the oil
#我先把锅给你烧热
I'm gonna heat the wok for you
#腌个十来分钟才合适呢
It'd be better to marinate the chicken for more than 10 minutes
#二伯的手法 技巧很高
Erbai is using a tricky technique
#待会炒这宫保鸡丁
When we cook the Kungpao chicken later
#煸锅就不用搁花椒了
We don't need to fry sichuan peppercorn first
#使这菜肴更加漂亮
That's making the dish look better
#味道又不失味道
While the flavor (of peppercorn) remains in the dish
#看见没有 看三叔溜锅
See that? Watch Sanshu "liu" (greasing) the wok
#咱们这锅啊 为什么有人说
The wok... Why some people asking
#滑油为什么扒锅呢
Why does the chicken stick to the wok during "hua you" (pre-frying)?
#因为你锅没烧到位
That's because the wok is not heated to the point
#咱们烧到冒烟的时候
When you see the smoke
#你看见没有 凉油搁进去
See that? Pour some cool oil inside
#看见没有咱们再转一下
Swirl the wok
#回到碗里 再回来等一下 行了
Pour the oil into a bowl, and put the wok back on heat. Done.
#什么时候下肉呢
When so we put the chicken into the wok?
#将近五成（油温）了
When the oil is about 50% hot (~150 degrees Celcius)
#五成热油温
50% hot oil
#下去之后别着急 先不动
Don't be hasty. Leave it
#小抖搂锅 让网友学一个过程
Slightly shake the wok. Let our friends learn about the process
#看见没有 网友们看清楚啊
You see? Take a careful look at this
#我们专业术语叫用筷子趟一下
In our term, this is called "tang" (stir) the chicken with chopsticks
#看见没有网友们 它不会扒锅的
My friends, (the chicken) won't stick to the wok
#看见没有 这叫滑油
See? This is "hua you" (pre-frying)
#一点都不粘
Not sticky at all
#搁上花椒油了 炸辣椒
Now pouring the peppercorn oil to fry the chili pepper
#它得慢慢煸
Fry it very slowly
#现在一炸容易糊 那就不对了
If the chili pepper is burnt, it's wrong
#它那是炝辣椒 咱们是炒辣椒
That's "qiang" (burn-fry) chili pepper, but we need to stir-fry it here
#网友们看清楚了
Look at this guys
#这是炒辣椒 小火慢炒
This is stir-frying. Slowly with low heat
#要在一分半到两分钟
After 1.5 or 2 minutes
#才能出来这香味
The aroma will be released
#跟三叔配合默契啊 对
-Collaborating well with Sanshu -Right.
#因为我也懂
Because I also understand (the principles)
#葱姜蒜
Spring onion, ginger, and garlic
#这里没有字幕
#开大火
Turn to high heat
#烹汁儿
Boil the sauce     #这里不确定是boil，还是简单地指把汁倒进去
#花生米 油
Peanuts, oil
#花生米 宫保鸡丁
Peanuts. That's Kungpao chicken
#转起来 走起来 出锅
Swirl the wok! Ready to serve!
#香 漂亮
Smells good. Beautiful!
#宫保鸡丁 老传统老味道
Kungpao chicken. Old tradition, old flavor
#麻 辣 鲜 香 脆
Numbing, spicy, umami, aromatic, crispy
#这东西得有辈分啊 我再换个勺
We need to stick to the order of age. Let me change a spoon
#宫保鸡丁 无法用语言来表达了
Kungpao chicken. Can't describe it with any language
#谢谢师父
Thank you master
#你看 这叫规矩
Look. This is the order
#三叔尝完了 你尝
After Sanshu tastes it, it's your turn
#最后是你徒弟
Your student is the last one
#谢谢师爷 好了
Thank you old master. That's it
#三叔知道 这加了多少葱啊
Sanshu knows. I've added much spring onion into this dish
#但是你看不出来 为什么香啊 出味
But you can't see that much actually. Why is this dish tasty? The spring onion provides the flavor
#炒宫保鸡丁 最后翻勺要转锅
When you cook Kungpao chicken, remember to swirl the wok at last
#淀粉一转就亮
The starch becomes shiny once you swirl the wok
#这里没有字幕
#片尾无需翻译。仅标注“我是大爷”这句话的开始时刻即可，精确到 0.1 秒 00:07:52,000